christiandatingforfree.com 2019-12-29

# Privacy Policy - Christian Dating For Free | Online Community of Single Christians

### Christian Dating For Free PRIVACY POLICY 

CDFF is committed to respecting the privacy rights of users of the Website (all capitalized terms not defined in this notice have the same meanings as in CDFF’s [Website Terms of Use](https://www.christiandatingforfree.com/terms.php), which is incorporated herein by reference). CDFF created this Privacy Policy to give You confidence as You visit and use the Website, and to demonstrate its commitment to fair information practices and to the protection of privacy.

This Privacy Policy is only applicable to the Website and not to any Third-Party Websites, which may have data collection, storage and use practices and policies that differ materially from this Privacy Policy.  For additional information, see the section concerning Third-Party Websites, below.

BY USING THE WEBSITE, YOU REPRESENT AND WARRANT THAT YOU HAVE READ AND UNDERSTOOD, AND AGREE TO THE TERMS OF, THIS PRIVACY POLICY.  IF YOU DO NOT UNDERSTAND OR DO NOT AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU MUST IMMEDIATELY LEAVE THE WEBSITE.

Each time You use the Website, the then-current version of this Privacy Policy will apply.  Accordingly, each time You use the Website You should check the date of this Privacy Policy (which appears at the end) and review any changes since the last time You used the Website.  For additional information, see the section concerning Updates and Changes to Privacy Policy, below.

 **1.   CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**

CDFF does not solicit or knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 14.  If CDFF obtains actual knowledge that it has collected personally identifiable information from a child under the age of 14, CDFF will immediately delete such information from its database.  Because CDFF does not collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 14, CDFF has no such information to use or disclose to third parties. CDFF has designed this Privacy Policy in order to comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Act (COPPA). 

**2.   INFORMATION COLLECTION PRACTICES**

**(a) Traffic Data.  ** Like most website operators, CDFF automatically gathers information of the sort that browsers automatically make available, including: (i) IP addresses; (ii) domain servers; (iii) types of computers accessing the Website; and (iv) types of Web browsers accessing the Website (collectively “ **Traffic Data** ”).  Traffic Data is anonymous information that does not personally identify You. 

**(b) Cookies.   ** A “ **Cookie** ” is a string of information that a website stores on a user’s computer, and that the user’s browser provides to the website each time the user submits a query to the website.  The purpose of a Cookie is to identify the user as a unique user of the Website. CDFF uses Cookies to customize Your experience on the Website to Your interests, to ensure that You do not see the same advertisements or informational messages repeatedly, and to store Your password so You do not have to re-enter it each time You visit the Website.  For additional information on CDFF’ uses of Cookies, see the section concerning Information Use and Disclosure Practices/Traffic Data and Information Gathered Using Cookies, below.

IF YOU DO NOT WISH TO HAVE COOKIES PLACED ON YOUR COMPUTER, YOU SHOULD SET YOUR BROWSERS TO REFUSE COOKIES BEFORE ACCESSING THE WEBSITE, WITH THE UNDERSTANDING THAT CERTAIN OF THE SERVICES AND CERTAIN FEATURES OF THE WEBSITE MAY NOT FUNCTION PROPERLY WITHOUT THE AID OF COOKIES.  IF YOU REFUSE COOKIES, YOU ASSUME ALL RESPONSIBILITY FOR ANY RESULTING LOSS OF FUNCTIONALITY.

**(c) Third-Party Advertising.** CDFF uses third-party advertising companies to serve ads when You visit the Website. These companies may use information (not including Personal Information, as defined below) about Your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to You. If You would like more information about this practice and to know Your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here:  [](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html)[http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

**(d) Personal Information.  ** In order for You to use certain of the Services, You may be asked to provide CDFF certain information that personally identifies You (“ **Personal Information** ”). Personal Information includes, without limitation: (1) “ **Contact Data** ” (such as Your name and e-mail address); and (2) “ **Demographic Data** ” (such as Your age, gender, ethnicity, height, weight, hair color, likes and dislikes, profession, education level, marital status, religious affiliation, parental status, smoking and drinking habits, country, state, city and zip code). In each case, You will be asked to provide Personal Information; the Website will not gather it surreptitiously.  CDFF may supplement the Personal Information You provide with additional Personal Information gathered from public sources or from third-parties (e.g., consumer reporting agencies) who may lawfully provide such information to CDFF. 

You are under no obligation to provide Personal Information, with the caveat that Your refusal to do so may prevent You from using certain of the Services.

**(e) Information You Make Public.  ** The Website contains features ( _e.g._ public profiles, chat rooms, forums, and message boards) that permit You to upload, post, transmit, display, perform or distribute content, information or other, including Your Personal Information. Any information that You choose to disclose by means of such features becomes public information over which CDFF is unable to exercise control. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose Your Personal Information by means of such features, and You agree to assume all responsibility for doing so.  

**3.   INFORMATION USE AND DISCLOSURE PRACTICES**

**(a) Traffic Data and Information Gathered Using Cookies** CDFF analyzes Traffic Data and information gathered using Cookies to help CDFF better understand who is using the Website and how they are using it.  By identifying patterns and trends in usage, CDFF is able to better design the Website to improve Your experience, and to serve You more relevant and interesting content and advertisements.  From time to time, CDFF may release Traffic Data and information gathered using Cookies in the aggregate, such as by publishing a report on trends in the usage of the Website. CDFF does not attempt to link information gathered using Cookies to Personal Information

**(b) Personal Information**

**(i) Generally.  ** CDFF uses Your Contact Data to send You information about CDFF and CDFF ’ products and services, and to contact You when necessary in connection with the Services.  CDFF uses Your Demographic Data to customize and tailor Your experience on the Website.  As with Traffic Data and information gathered using Cookies, from time to time CDFF may release Demographic Data in the aggregate, such as by publishing a report on trends in the usage of the Website.

**(ii) Disclosure Practices**

Except under the following circumstances, CDFF will keep Your Personal Information private, and will not share it with third parties.

  * **Disclosure in Connection with Services.  ** CDFF discloses Personal Information to those who help it provide Services, including those who perform technical, administrative and data processing tasks such as hosting, billing, fulfillment, and data storage and security. 
  * **License to User Content.  ** As stated in the Website Terms of Use, by using the Website, You grant the CDFF Parties the right to publish Your name and any username of Yours in connection with the CDFF Parties’ exercise of their license in and to Your User Content.  You further waive any claims arising from the CDFF Parties’ exercise of that right.  For additional information, see Terms of Use Section 14, regarding User Content.
  * **By Law or to Protect Rights.  ** CDFF discloses Personal Information when required to do so by law, or in response to a subpoena or court order, or when CDFF believes in its sole discretion that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of CDFF , third parties or the public at large. 

  * **Business Transfers; Bankruptcy.  ** CDFF reserves the right to transfer all Personal Information in its possession to a successor organization in the event of a merger, acquisition, or bankruptcy or other sale of all or a portion of CDFF ’ assets.  Other than to the extent ordered by a bankruptcy or other court, the use and disclosure of all transferred Personal Information will be subject to this Privacy Policy, or to a new privacy policy if You are given notice of that new privacy policy and an opportunity to affirmatively opt-out of it.  Personal Information submitted or collected after a transfer, however, may be subject to a new privacy policy adopted by CDFF ’ successor organization. 

  * **Disclosure to Marketing Partners.  ** From time to time, CDFF will disclose Your Personal Information to marketing partners of CDFF, so that those marketing partners may send you offers by email that may be of interest to you.  We allow third-party companies to collect certain information when you visit our web site. These companies may utilize cookies, pixels or other technologies to collect and use both personally identifiable information (e.g., your name, phone number, physical or electronic address) and non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit the websites of the Digital Advertising Alliance at [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/) or Networking Advertising Initiative at [www.networkadvertising.org/choices](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices). California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of Company who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of their personally identifiable information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. You may request a list of all of the third parties with whom we share your PII by sending an e-mail to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#0a6b6e6763644a69627863797e636b646e6b7e63646d6c65786c786f6f24696567) and place "California Third Party Disclosure" in the subject line. Please allow up to thirty days for a response. 

  * When you access our Service through android or ios application, we and a third party partner may receive or collect and store the advertising identification number associated with your device and, depending on your mobile device settings, your geographical location data, including GPS coordinates (such as latitude and/or longitude) or similar information regarding the location of your mobile device. You may enable or disable the collection of this data at any time using the settings on your mobile device by: (a) deleting the app or (b) deleting or resetting the applicable mobile advertiser ID by limiting ad tracking on your device. You may also use the Digital Advertising Alliances �AppChoices� application (available at <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices>) to opt out of participating third party advertising networks who target advertising to your mobile device based on your mobile advertising identifier. 

**4.   CONSENT TO RECEIVE EMAIL FROM CDFF**

As stated in the [Website Terms of Use](https://www.christiandatingforfree.com/terms.php), by registering with the Website and becoming a Member, you thereby consent to receive periodic email communications regarding the Services, including activation emails.  As part of registration, You may also elect to receive periodic email communications regarding special offers and other promotions (collectively, “ **Special Offers** ”). You may opt-out of receiving Special Offers at any time by (a) editing Your “Account Settings;” (b) following the unsubscribe instructions contained in each Special Offer; or (c) sending an email to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#5130353c383f1132392338222538303f353025383f36373e23372334347f323e3c).

 **5.   SECURITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

CDFF has implemented and maintains reasonable security procedures and practices to protect against the unauthorized access, use, modification, destruction or disclosure of Your Personal Information.

 **6.   LOST OR STOLEN INFORMATION**

You must promptly notify us if Your user name or password is lost, stolen or used without permission.  In such an event, we will remove that user name or password from Your account and update our records accordingly.

 **7.   USER ABILITY TO ACCESS, UPDATE, AND CORRECT PERSONAL INFORMATION **

CDFF wants Your Personal Information to be complete and accurate.  As stated in the [Website Terms of Use](https://www.christiandatingforfree.com/terms.php), by using the Website, You represent and warrant that all information You provide on any registration form or otherwise in connection with Your use of the Website and Services will be complete and accurate, and that You will update that information as necessary to maintain its completeness and accuracy.  To confirm the completeness and accuracy of, or make changes to, Your Personal Information, visit Your personal profile.  Through Your personal profile You may review and update You Personal Information that we have already collected.

 **8.   THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES**

CDFF neither owns nor controls Third-Party Websites.  Accordingly, Third-Party Websites are under no obligation to comply with this Privacy Policy except with respect to Personal Information provided directly to them by CDFF . Before visiting or providing Personal Information to a Third-Party Website, You should inform Yourself of the privacy policies and practices (if any) of that Third-Party Website, and should take those steps necessary to, in Your discretion, protect Your privacy. 

 **9.   PROMOTIONAL ACTIVITIES**

From time to time, CDFF may conduct contests, giveaways and other promotions (collectively, “ **Promotional Activities** ”).  Any information submitted in connection with Promotional Activities will be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  From time to time, CDFF may also ask You to participate in surveys designed to help CDFF improve the Websites or Services. Any Personal Information provided to CDFF in connection with any survey will be used only in relation to that survey, and will be disclosed to third parties not bound by this Privacy Policy only in aggregated form.

 **10.   UPDATES AND CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, CDFF reserves the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, update, change or modify this Privacy Policy, simply by posting such update, change or modification on this page. Any such addition, update, change or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the Website.  Each time You use the Website, the then-current version of this Privacy Policy will apply.  Accordingly, each time You use the Website You should check the date of this Privacy Policy (which appears at the end) and review any changes since the last time You used the Website.  Unless CDFF obtains Your express consent, any revised Privacy Policy will apply only to information collected after the effective date of such revised Privacy Policy, and not to information collected under any earlier Privacy Policy.

Effective Date: August 28, 2015
